Md Mahin Arafat

Lippincott St, Toronto, ON M5T 2R5

+1 (647) 997-7035 - mahinarafatmeem@gmail.com

mdmahinarafat.netlify.app | github.com/mahin12 | http://linkedin.com/in/mahin-arafat

Summary

Currently a post-graduate student of Electrical and Computer Engineering at Ontario Tech University with 2 years of experience in web development with a strong understanding of software architecture, agile and scrum methodologies, JIRA, and Git. Motivated to work on digital transformation and innovation, software development life-cycle, cloud platform and looking for opportunities to grow.

Education

Ontario Tech University		
Masters of Engineering in Electrical and Computer Engineering CGPA 3.73/4.33		2022 - 2023
University of Malaya Bachelor of CS in Computer Science (Software Engineering) CGPA 3.24/4.0		2017 - 2021
To	ols & Skills	
Web development	• SUMO	Software Architectu

- Python, Django • JIRA, Heroku,
- Java, JavaScript Bootstrap
- HTML, CSS, SCSS

- Agile Methodology,
- Photoshop, Lightroom, FCPX
- and Modelling
- MS Office
- Source Control

Relevant Experience

Sirius App Messenger

Freelance Software Engineer

June 2022- Present

Helping with making a robust code base for upcoming projects

PHP

- Using React.JS and APIs on development
- Integrating the codebase
- Learning client management and understanding responsibilities to shape the project

Strativ BD Limited

Junior Software Engineer

Jun 2021 - Dec 2021

- Worked on different web development projects
- Learned to work on client-based projects, and attended and dealt with multiple clients
- Utilized knowledge in SQL, Python, Django, and JavaScript
- Changed the entire theme and added functionalities for the internal ERP system

Saleduck Asia

Web Application Developer Intern

Jan 2019 - Jan 2020

- Worked with the development and maintenance of various websites of Saleduck
- Worked in SASS, PHP, Laravel framework, HTML and CSS

- Used professional product management tools and developer tools like Bitbucket, Slack, Git, Docker etc.
- Learned the basics of backend development and database such as MySQL
- Followed and learned deeply and used the model, view and controller and used the components to maintain the system architecture
- Successfully worked in frontend development

Strativ BD Limited

Software Engineering Summer Intern

Jul 2018 - Sep 2018

- Participated in changing website designs according to the clients' requirements
- Learned how to make codes more effective and efficient using bootstrap tools

Projects

•	Data Visualization (<i>Tableau, Python</i>)	2022
•	Personal Portfolio Website (Gatsby, JavaScript)	2022
•	Vehicle Movement Detection based on Device Movement (Sumo, Python)	2022
•	Fire Hazard Detection System (Fortran, Python)	2022
•	Car Rental and Vehicle Breakdown assistant (Python, Django)	2020
•	Personal Finance System Website (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, React.js)	2018
•	Minimum Spanning Tree Finder (Python)	2018
•	Smart English Tutor (Software Requirement Engineering)	2018
•	Trello Landing Page (HTML, CSS, jQuery)	2018
•	Traffic Light System (Machine Language)	2017
•	Number Guessing Game A.I. (JAVA)	2017
•	Bank Management System (JAVA)	2017
•	Personal Blog (WordPress)	2016